Finding Aid for Victor F. Lemmer Papers 1860s-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Victor F. Lemmer Papers 1860s-1974, 1922-1974
Lemmer, Victor F.
2 oversize folders
9.5 linear feet
Ironwood, Michigan businessman and local historian; include correspondence, research notes and writings largely concerning the history of Gogebic County and Upper Peninsula iron mining; also papers concerning his work with the Gogebic Industrial Bureau.
851713 Aa 2; UAm; UAl
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection came from Mr. Lemmer (donor no. 2643 ) in several accessions between 1949 and 1974.
The collection is open for research.
Victor F. Lemmer was born in Escanaba, Michigan June 18, 1898, the son of immigrant parents from Luxembourg. Following his high school education, Lemmer worked as a country school teacher and as a bookkeeper with the William Bonifas Lumber Company. He then attended and graduated from the University of Notre Dame in 1926. After graduation he returned to the Bonifas Company, first at Escanaba and later at Marenisco. In 1929, he moved to Ironwood where he established an insurance business and where he resided for the rest of his life.
Through much of the 1930s, Lemmer worked as a bookkeeper and served in local government positions. In 1931 he became Gogebic County auditor, serving until 1939. In 1939, the mining companies of the area formed the Gogebic Industrial Bureau which was established as a taxpayers association. Because of his knowledge of the area and overall competence, Lemmer was chosen secretary of the organization and serving as public relations representative for the industry. Also in 1939 and with the approval of the Gogebic Industrial Bureau, Lemmer was chosen to serve on a temporary and part-time basis as coordinator of the state social welfare commission charged with the implementation of Michigan's new welfare and relief plan. Lemmer served briefly in Lansing then returned to Ironwood.
Lemmer's great love was the history and lore of Gogebic county. He was active in local and state historical societies and wrote and spoke extensively on the history of this region of the Upper Peninsula. He died in 1974.
The Victor Lemmer Papers concerns the history of the western portion of the Upper Peninsula of Michigan, particularly Gogebic County, as well as his work as the agent for the Gogebic Industrial Bureau. The collection has been divided into the following series: Correspondence; Photographs; Personal/Miscellaneous; Gogebic Industrial Bureau Files; Research Files; Collected Materials; and Writings/Speeches.
Subjects:
American newspapers--Michigan--Gogebic County.; Business records.; Champion (Mich.); Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931.; Fayette (Mich.); Frederic (Mich.); Gillen, Martin James, 1872-1943.; Gogebic County (Mich.); Gogebic Industrial Bureau.; Indians of North America--Michigan.; Iron mines and mining--Michigan--Upper Peninsula.; Ironwood (Mich.); Langford, Richard, 1826-1909.; Lemmer, Victor F.; Longyear, John Munro, 1850-1922.; Marenisco (Mich.); Merritt, D. H.; Norrie, A. Lanfear, 1858-1910.; Ontonagan (Mich.); Ottawa National Forest (Mich.); Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Wakefield (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Material:
Abbott, Bud.; Banks.; Buildings--Michigan--Ironwood.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Ironwood.; Children.; Costello, Lou.; Dwellings.; Fires.; Gogebic County (Mich.); Hotels and taverns.; Indians of North America.; Interiors.; Ironwood (Mich.)--Buildings.; Ironwood (Mich.)--Business enterprises.; Ironwood (Mich.); Iron mining.; Kalos (Ship); Langford, Richard, 1826-1909.; Lemmer, Victor F.; Lemmer family.; Lumber industry.; Marquette County (Mich.); Michigan. National Guard.; Mining.; Music--Michigan--Ironwood.; Soda fountains.; Spanish-American War, 1898.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Women.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1939-1945.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence dates from 1922 to 1974 and pertains to all phases of Lemmer's career and interests. During World War II, Lemmer corresponded with Ironwood and Gogebic County men serving in the military. There are several folders of these exchanges.
  - Letters from Charles Berrigan and Rev. Erasmus Dooley, both in service during World War I 1918-1919 (Box 1)
    include some photos
  - 1922-1939 (Box 1)
    (1-1)
  - 1940 (Box 1)
    (1-2)
  - 1941 (Box 1)
    (1-3)
  - 1942 (Box 1)
    (1-4)
  - January-April 1943 (Box 1)
    (1-5)
  - May-July 1943 (Box 1)
    (1-6)
  - August-December 1943 (Box 1)
    (1-7)
  - 1944 (Box 1)
    (1-8)
  - January-August 1945 (Box 1)
    (1-9)
  - World War II undated, 2 folders (Box 1)
    (1-11--1-11a)
  - 1946 (Box 1)
    (1-12)
  - 1947 (Box 1)
    (1-13)
  - 1948 (Box 1)
    (1-14)
  - 1949 (Box 1)
    (1-15)
  - 1950 (Box 1)
    (1-16)
  - 1951 (Box 1)
    (1-17)
  - 1952 (Box 1)
    (1-18)
  - 1953 (Box 1)
    (1-19)
  - January-August 1954 (Box 1)
    (1-20)
  - September-December 1954 (Box 1)
    (1-21)
  - 1955 (Box 1)
    (1-22)
  - January-June 1956 (Box 1)
    (1-23)
  - July-December 1956 (Box 1)
    (1-24)
  - January-April 1957 (Box 1)
    (1-25)
  - May-August 1957 (Box 1)
    (1-26)
  - September-December 1957 (Box 1)
    (1-27)
  - January-June 1959 (Box 1)
    (1-29)
  - July-December 1959 (Box 1)
    (1-30)
  - January-April 1960 (Box 1)
    (1-31)
  - May-December 1960 (Box 1)
    (1-32)
  - January-June 1961 (Box 1)
    (1-33)
  - July-December 1961 (Box 1)
    (1-34)
  - January-April 1962 (Box 1)
    (1-35)
  - May-September 1962 (Box 1)
    (1-36)
  - October-December 1962 (Box 1)
    (1-37)
  - January-March 1963 (Box 1)
    (1-38)
  - April-September 1963 (Box 1)
    (1-39)
  - October-December 1963 (Box 1)
    (1-40)
  - January-March 1964 (Box 1)
    (1-41)
  - April-July 1964 (Box 1)
    (1-42)
  - August-December 1964 (Box 1)
    (1-43)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
    (1-44)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
    (1-45)
  - 1967 (Box 1)
    (1-46)
  - January-March 1968 (Box 2)
    (2-1)
  - April 1968 (Box 2)
    (2-2)
  - May-June 1968 (Box 2)
    (2-3)
  - July-August 1968 (Box 2)
    (2-4)
  - September-December 1968 (Box 2)
    (2-5)
  - January-March 1969 (Box 2)
    (2-6)
  - April 1969 (Box 2)
    (2-7)
  - May-July 1969 (Box 2)
    (2-8)
  - August-September 1969 (Box 2)
    (2-9)
  - October-November 1969 (Box 2)
    (2-10)
  - December 1969 (Box 2)
    (2-11)
  - January-August 1970 (Box 2)
    (2-12)
  - September-December 1970 (Box 2)
    (2-13)
  - 1971 (Box 2)
    (2-14)
  - 1972 (Box 2)
    (2-15)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    (2-16)
  - Undated (Box 2)
    (2-17)
- Photographs
  The Photographs relate to lumbering activity near Ironwood, Michigan, and to iron exploration and mining; photos of Ironwood businesses, buildings, and social organizations; photos of nearby recreation areas; and photographs of soldiers from Ironwood who served in the World Wars I and II. Most of these photos were collected by Lemmer in his efforts to preserve the history of this section of the Upper Peninsula, thus this series includes the earliest dated materials in the collection.
  - Buildings, Ironwood (Curry Hotel, Ironwood Times Building, restaurant (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Library, Ironwood school (Box 2)
  - Cave-ins, Ironwood area 1957 (Box 2)
  - Fire in Ironwood business section 1945 (Box 2)
  - Groups-Military, police, sports (include 5th Regiment (Box 2)
  - Michigan National Guard) (Box 2)
    see also photo of fire department in oversize folder UAm)
  - Groups-Social (Box 2)
    include World's Fair Band, 1901
  - Indians (trails, cemetery, etc.) (Box 2)
  - Individuals (Box 2)
  - Interiors, business and residences, copies of early photos (Box 2)
  - Iron ore booklet revision ideas July 14, 1961 (Box 2)
  - Landscapes, waterfalls (Box 2)
  - Langford, Richard (Box 2)
  - Lemmer and family (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Benton W. (Box 2)
  - Little Girl's Point (Box 2)
  - Lumbering (Box 2)
    also in oversize folder UAl
  - Mines-Aurora, Colby, Eureka, Pabst, Puritan, Quincy (Box 2)
  - Mines-Castile Mining Co. (Box 2)
  - Mines-Ironwood, including Newport, Norrie, Anvil (Box 2)
    also in oversize folder UAm
  - Mines-Ontonagon Company: White Pine Copper Mine (Box 2)
  - Mines-Peterson, Triplett (Box 2)
  - Mines-Wakefield, including Ronn's, Sunday Lake (Box 2)
  - Mining-General, including exploration 1863, 1866 (Box 2)
  - Mining-Unidentified (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (include ship Kalos) (Box 2)
  - Norrie Park (Box 2)
  - Recreation areas-Miscellaneous: Black River Harbor, Echo Lake, Gogebic Extension Camp, Ottawa National Forest (Box 2)
  - Sylvania Recreation Area (Box 2)
  - Trees-Indian Trailmarkers (Box 2)
  - Views, Ironwood (Box 2)
  - Wartime subjects (including Abbott and Costello visit) (Box 3)
  - World War I soldiers from Ironwood and vicinity (Box 3)
  - World War II soldiers from Ironwood and vicinity (Box 3)
- Personal/Miscellaneous
  The Personal/Miscellaneous series includes biographical information, clippings about Lemmer and his career, and scattered other documents pertaining to Lemmer's service as county auditor and as head of the state welfare commission.
  - Citations, biographical (Box 3)
  - Clippings (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea re service in part as county auditor and with the state welfare commission 1934-1940 (Box 3)
  - Testimony given the matter of the Petition for the Removal of R. B. Wortley, Roderick McDonald and Hjalmer Turpeinen, as members of the Gogebic County Road Commission 1938 (Box 3)
    (Lemmer testified as county auditor)
  - World War II Press Releases on Michigan Servicemen, 6 folders (Box 4)
    (4-1--4-6)
- Gogebic Industrial Bureau Files
  The Gogebic Industrial Bureau Files contain reports, studies, and other materials from Lemmer's service as agent of this mine owners organization. Much of this series relates to matters of taxation.
  - Annual Report of the Agent
    - 1958 (Box 4)
      (4-7)
    - 1959 (Box 4)
      (4-8)
    - 1960 (Box 4)
      (4-9)
    - 1961 (Box 4)
      (4-10)
    - 1962 (Box 4)
      (4-11)
  - Monthly Review of Governmental Activities on the Iron Range
    - 1957 (Box 4)
      (4-12)
    - 1958 (Box 4)
      (4-13)
    - 1959 (Box 4)
      (4-14)
  - Upper Peninsula Population
    - 1940-1970 (Box 4)
      (4-15)
    - 1950 census, in black binder (Box 4)
    - 1960 census (Box 4)
      (4-16)
    - 1960 study, in brown binder (Box 4)
  - Upper Peninsula Labor Force, Miscellaneous data (Box 4)
    (4-17)
  - Gogebic School Finances 1957-1958 (Box 4)
    (4-18)
  - Gogebic Planning Commission, Mineral Committee March 21, 1962 (Box 4)
    (4-18a)
  - Gogebic County School Finances 1959-1960 (Box 4)
    (4-19)
  - Gogebic County School Finances, Miscellaneous 1950-1965 (Box 4)
    (4-20)
  - Gogebic County Resources Workshop for Teachers (Box 4)
    (4-21)
  - Freedom Forum XVIII 1957, 2 folders (Box 4)
    (4-22--23)
  - Gogebic County Schools, Miscellaneous 1955-1960s (Box 5)
    (5-1)
  - Ervin Township School District (Box 5)
    (5-2)
  - Final Tax Valuations for Gogebic & Iron Counties 1940-1954 (Box 5)
    (5-3)
  - Gogebic County Equalization Study 1951 (Box 5)
    (5-4)
  - Gogebic County, Reports of Committee on Apportionment 1954-1972 (Box 5)
    (5-5)
  - Gogebic County, Miscellaneous Revenue & Tax Data 1957-1959 (Box 5)
    (5-6)
  - Gogebic County Tax Treatise 1957 (Box 5)
    (5-7)
  - Gogebic County Tax Treatise 1958 (Box 5)
    (5-8)
  - All Michigan Counties, Valuations 1959 (Box 5)
    (5-9)
  - Gogebic County, Tax Treatise 1960 (Box 5)
    (5-10)
  - Gogebic County Tax Compilation 1950-1959 (Box 5)
    (5-11)
  - Gogebic County, Twenty Year Tax Treatise 1940-1959 (Box 5)
    (5-12)
  - Gogebic County Budgets 1964-1967 (Box 5)
    (5-13)
  - Miscellaneous Tax Data 1950-1962 (Box 5)
    (5-14)
  - Valuation of All Mines in Gogebic County 1940-1954 (Box 5)
    (5-15)
  - Pickands Mather & Co. Taxes 1958-1962 (Box 5)
    (5-16)
  - Review of Taxation of Michigan Mines 1957 (Box 5)
    (5-17)
  - Gogebic County, Taxes on Mining & Non-mining Property 1953-1959 (Box 5)
    (5-18)
  - Michigan Iron & Copper Mine Valuations 1961-1962 (Box 5)
    (5-19)
  - Michigan Iron & Copper Mine Valuations 1962-1963 (Box 5)
    (5-20)
  - Miscellaneous Mining Tax Data 1955-1957 (Box 5)
    (5-21)
  - Cost & Production of Michigan Iron Mines 1944-1952 (Box 5)
    (5-22)
  - Cost & Production of Michigan Iron Mines 1953-1958 (Box 5)
    (5-23)
  - Cost & Production of Michigan Iron Mines 1959-1962 (Box 5)
    (5-24)
  - Cost & Production of Michigan Iron Mines 1963-1968 (Box 5)
    (5-25)
  - Iron Ore Shipments 1854-1968 (Box 5)
    (5-26)
  - Two Mining Leases 1957-1958 (Box 5)
    (5-27)
  - Mineral Resources of Michigan 1954 (Box 6)
    (6-1)
  - Michigan's Mineral Industry 1957 (Box 6)
    (6-2)
  - Michigan's Mineral Industry 1962 (Box 6)
    (6-3)
  - Michigan's Mineral Industry 1964, 1965, 1966 (Box 6)
    (6-4)
  - Gogebic County Economic and Physical Planning 1963 (Box 6)
    (6-5)
  - Iron Ore, US Tariff Commission Report, No. 35 (Box 6)
    (6-6)
  - Report on Iron Mining ... Gogebic Iron Range 1961 (Box 6)
    (6-7)
  - Competitive Position of Lake Superior Iron Ore 1960 (Box 6)
    (6-8)
  - Operation Gladstone 1966 (Box 6)
    (6-9)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 6)
    (6-10--6-13)
  - Miscellaneous Bibliographies (Box 6)
    (6-14)
  - Michigan Historical Societies (Box 6)
    (6-15)
  - Summer Conference of the Michigan Historical Commission 1954 (Box 6)
    (6-16)
  - Gogebic County Historical Society (Box 6)
    (6-17)
- Research Files
  The Research Files are arranged alphabetically by topic on which Lemmer collected information (clippings, writings of others, notes, etc.). Topics for which there are multiple folders are the Gogebic Iron Range, Indians, Missionaries and explorers, and Gogebic County.
  - Bessemer, Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    (6-18)
  - Champion, History of (Box 6)
    (6-19)
  - Civil War Data, Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    (6-20)
  - Copper Mining (Box 6)
    (6-21)
  - Delta County (Box 6)
    (6-22)
  - Edison's Experiments with Iron Ore, 3 folders (Box 6)
    (6-23--6-25)
  - Fayette, Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    (6-26)
  - Ford River, Town of (Box 6)
    (6-27)
  - Frederic: Typical Logging Village (Box 6)
    (6-28)
  - Gillen, Martin J., 3 folders (Box 6)
    (6-29-6-31)
  - Gogebic County-Historical Attractions of (Box 6)
    (6-32)
  - Gogebic County-Lake Gazetteer (Box 6)
    (6-33)
  - Gogebic County-History of Ervin Township (Box 7)
    (7-1)
  - Gogebic County-Mural (Box 7)
    (7-2)
  - Gogebic County-Miscellaneous Data, 2 folders (Box 7)
    (7-3--7-4)
  - Gogebic Iron Range
    - History by J. Gill (Box 7)
      (7-5)
    - Influence of Swedish Settlers on (Box 7)
      (7-6)
    - Iron Mining on (Box 7)
      (7-7)
    - Gogebic Iron Range and its Bright Metropolis, Bessemer (Box 7)
      (7-8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
      (7-9)
  - Gold Mining in the Upper Peninsula (Box 7)
    (7-10)
  - Historical Sites and Markers, 2 folders (Box 7)
    (7-11--7-12)
  - Holzhey's Stage Coach Robbery, 2 folders (Box 7)
    (7-13--7-14)
  - Indians
    - Memoir ... 1718 (Box 7)
      (7-15)
    - An Early Historic Cemetery at St. Ignace (Box 7)
      (7-16)
    - Map of Michigan in the Indian Language (Box 7)
      (7-17)
    - Chippewa Legends (Box 7)
      (7-18)
    - Chief Buffalo Grant (Box 7)
      (7-19)
    - Areas of Occupancy by Tribes of Michigan (Box 7)
      (7-20)
    - Report of Socio-Economic Survey of Michigan Indian Groups (1951) (Box 7)
      (7-21)
    - Indians of Michigan and Their Present Status (1953) (Box 7)
      (7-22)
    - Miscellaneous Data, 4 folders (Box 7)
      (7-23--7-26)
  - Iron Mining-Miscellaneous Data, 6 folders (Box 7)
    (7-27--7-32)
  - Ironwood, History of, by W.T. Alleva (1972) (Box 7)
    (7-33)
  - Ironwood, Histories of, Miscellaneous (Box 7)
    (7-34)
  - Ironwood, History of the School District ... 1885-1926 by J.S. Monroe (Box 7)
    (7-35)
  - Ironwood, Miscellaneous Data, 2 folders (Box 7)
    (7-36--7-37)
  - Langford, Richard (Box 7)
    (7-38)
  - Longyear, J.M. (Box 7)
    (7-39)
  - Lumbering (Box 7)
    (7-40)
  - Mackinac (Box 7)
    (7-41)
  - Mackinac Bridge, History of (Box 7)
    (7-42)
  - Marenisco, History (Box 7)
    (7-43)
  - Marquette Iron Range, History of (Box 7)
    (7-44)
  - Michigan Boundaries (Box 7)
    (7-45)
  - Michigan, Historical (Box 7)
    (7-46)
  - Michigan Historical Commission Information Leaflets (Box 7)
    (7-47)
  - Military Road (Box 7)
    (7-48)
  - Mercer, History of (Box 8)
    (8-1)
  - Missionaries and Explorers-"Black Goun Tree" (Box 8)
    (8-2)
  - Missionaries and Explorers-Pere Marquette Pageant (Box 8)
    (8-3)
  - Missionaries and Explorers-Pere Rene Menard (Box 8)
    (8-4)
  - Missionaries and Explorers-Miscellaneous Data (Box 8)
    (8-5)
  - Morgan, Henry Lewis (Box 8)
    (8-6)
  - Natural History, 3 folders (Box 8)
    (8-7--8-9)
  - Newspapers of the UP (Box 8)
    (8-10)
  - Norrie, A. Lanfear (Box 8)
    (8-11)
  - Ontonagon (Box 8)
    (8-12)
  - Ottawa National Forest, Fact Sheets 1957 (Box 8)
    (8-13)
  - Ottawa National Forest, History of (Box 8)
    (8-14)
  - Ottawa National Forest-Miscellaneous (Box 8)
    (8-15)
  - Presque Isle River (Box 8)
    (8-16)
  - Railroad and Trolley Development (Box 8)
    (8-17)
  - Telecommunications (Box 8)
    (8-18)
  - Tourist Promotion, 2 folders (Box 8)
    (8-19--8-20)
  - Upper Peninsula, Histories of (Box 8)
    (8-21)
  - Van Riper, Dr. Paul (interview) (Box 8)
    (8-22)
  - Voyageur Lands Corporation (Box 8)
    (8-23)
  - Wakefield, History of (Box 8)
    (8-24)
  - Wakefield, Miscellaneous (Box 8)
    (8-25)
  - Miscellaneous Historical Data, 2 folders (Box 8)
    (8-26--8-27)
- Collected Materials
  Collected Materials consist of original documentation collected by Lemmer relating to the history of his region. Most important is the three volume history of Gogebic County prepared by the Writer's Program of the WPA during the New Deal. This volume was never published and this manuscript, according to Lemmer, is all that survived.
  - W.P.A. History of Gogebic County, 1 manuscript bound (in 3 volumes) (Box 8)
  - Gogebic County, Grand Jury Investigation of County Government 1943 (Box 9)
    (9-1)
  - Gogebic County, Township Boundaries 1864-1885 (Box 9)
    (9-2)
  - Gogebic County, Miscellaneous Government Finance 1902-1936 (Box 9)
    (9-3)
  - Gogebic County, Miscellaneous Government Correspondence & Legal Documents 1873-1917 (Box 9)
    (9-4)
  - Iron Mining Analysis of Steel & Tube Company of America 1911-1920 (Box 9)
    (9-5)
  - Iron Mining, Miscellaneous 1890-1921 (Box 9)
    (9-6)
  - Lands, Miscellaneous 1862-1938 (Box 9)
    (9-7)
  - Lubben Estate, Appraisal of 1927-1928 (Box 9)
    (9-8)
  - D.H. Merritt, Property Records 1885-1894 (Box 9)
    (9-9)
  - D.H. Merritt, Property Records 1895-1915 (Box 9)
    (9-10)
  - D.H. Merritt, and C.H. Call, Bessemer Lots 1898 (Box 9)
    (9-11)
  - Military Road, Petition for Route Change 1867 (Box 9)
    (9-12)
  - Social Welfare, Analysis of State Department of circa 1940 (Box 9)
    (9-13)
  - Practical Notes on Surveys by W.H. Hearding (1872) (Box 9)
  - Scrapbooks re Michigan Week activities 1955, 1957, 2 volumes (Box 9)
- Writings/Speeches
  The Writings/Speeches series contains most of Lemmer's writings on Gogebic and Upper Peninsula history. This series also includes his poetry and humorous pieces published in the Chicago Tribune Column "In the Wake of the News" in the period 1929-1968.
  - AB thesis from Notre Dame University re proposed child labor amendment 1926 (Box 10)
    (10-1)
  - Relating to Upper Peninsula
    - $8.55 Outlay Started Boom (Box 10)
      (10-2)
    - When the Penokee-Gogebic Range Was Young (Box 10)
      (10-3)
    - Starts Factory in Woodshed (Box 10)
      (10-4)
    - Under the Court House Steeple (Box 10)
      (10-5)
    - Brief History of the Gogebic Iron Range (Box 10)
      (10-6)
    - History of Architecture: Gogebic County (Box 10)
      (10-7)
    - History of Little Girl's Point (Box 10)
      (10-8)
    - How Little Girl's Point Got its Names (Box 10)
      (10-9)
    - Gogebic Stagecoach Robbery (Box 10)
      (10-10)
    - History of the City of Ironwood (Box 10)
      (10-11)
    - A Work of Art (Box 10)
      (10-12)
    - Historical Facts for Gogebic County: Michigan Week 1955 (Box 10)
      (10-13)
    - Biography of Edward Biddle and the Biddle family (Box 10)
      (10-14)
    - What the Iron Ore Industry Means to Gogebic County (Box 10)
      (10-15)
    - Arch Bridge on the Black River (Box 10)
      (10-16)
    - Delta County Historical Data Available in the Archives of the Michigan Historical Commission (Box 10)
      (10-17)
    - Little Known Facts of Gogebic County (Box 10)
      (10-18)
    - Michigan Low Grade Ores (Box 10)
      (10-19)
    - What the Iron Ore Mining Industry Means to Iron County and Hurley (Box 10)
      (10-20)
    - The Two Party System (Box 10)
      (10-21)
    - Biography of Martin J. Gillen (Box 10)
      (10-22)
    - Little Known Facts about Ontonagon County (Box 10)
      (10-23)
    - Story of the First Telephones in the Upper Peninsula (Box 10)
      (10-24)
    - Early Telephone Development in the Upper Peninsula (Box 10)
      (10-25)
    - Our Way of Life in Our American Republic (Box 10)
      (10-26)
    - Michigan's Gem Stones (Box 10)
      (10-27)
    - Richard Langford and the Discovery of the Colby Mines (Box 10)
      (10-28)
    - Peninsula's Pre-Historic Copper Miners (Box 10)
      (10-29)
    - Story of A. Lanfear Norrie (Box 10)
      (10-30)
    - Michigan Postal History: Gogebic County (Box 10)
      (10-31)
    - Impact of the Civil War on Iron Ore Mining in Michigan (Box 10)
      (10-32)
    - The Apostle Islands (Box 10)
      (10-33)
    - Wireless Telegraphy (Box 10)
      (10-34)
    - Two Way Communications (Box 10)
      (10-35)
    - Diary of European-Asian-African Trip (Box 10)
      (10-36)
    - Upper Peninsula Work Force Commutes to New Job (Box 10)
      (10-37)
    - Speech to St. Louis County (Minn.) Historical Society (Box 10)
      (10-38)
    - Early History of the Lake Superior District (Box 10)
      (10-39)
    - Employees Award Speech (Wakefield Hospital) (Box 10)
      (10-40)
    - Where is Everybody in Gogebic County (Box 10)
      (10-41)
    - Pioneering with Taconite (Book review of) (Box 10)
      (10-42)
    - History of the County of Gogebic (Box 10)
      (10-43)
    - The Year 1888 on the Gogebic Range (Box 10)
      (10-44)
    - Ghost Mines of the Gogebic Range (Box 10)
      (10-45)
    - Chronological History of Gogebic County 1620-1968 (Box 10)
      (10-46)
    - Ironwood Michigan (Box 10)
      (10-47)
    - Thomas Edison's Experimental Work with Michigan Iron Ore (Box 10)
      (10-48)
    - The Gogebic Explorer (Box 10)
      (10-49)
    - Meaning of the Word Gogebic (Box 10)
      (10-50)
    - Discovery of Iron Ore on the Newport Hill (Box 10)
      (10-51)
    - Iron Industry (untitled) undated (Box 10)
      (10-52)
  - Contributions to the Chicago Tribune Column "In the Wake of the News"
    - 1929-1947 (Box 10)
      (10-53)
    - 1947-1951 (Box 10)
      (10-54)
    - 1951-1954 (Box 10)
      (10-55)
    - 1958 (Box 10)
      (10-56)
    - January-June 1959 (Box 10)
      (10-57)
    - July-December 1959 (Box 10)
      (10-58)
    - 1962-1963 (Box 10)
      (10-59)
    - 1964-1968 (Box 10)
      (10-60)
    - Undated, 3 folders (Box 10)
      (10-61--10-63)
    - Chicago Tribune Memorabilia (Box 10)
      (10-64)